<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<bank>
  <topic>PDE14 - Brain Dump (google.lead2pass.professional-data-engineer.rapidshare.2024-mar-12.by.timothy.116q.vce)</topic>
  <!-- STRUCTURE DEFINITION:
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>XXX</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>XXX</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  -->

  <entry>
    <question>Your software uses a simple JSON format for all messages. These messages are published to Google Cloud Pub/Sub, then processed with Google Cloud Dataflow to create a real-time dashboard for the CFO. During testing, you notice that some messages are missing in the dashboard. You check the logs, and all messages are being published to Cloud Pub/Sub successfully. What should you do next?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Check the dashboard application to see if it is not displaying correctly.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Run a fixed dataset through the Cloud Dataflow pipeline and analyze the output.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use Google Stackdriver Monitoring on Cloud Pub/Sub to find the missing messages.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Switch Cloud Dataflow to pull messages from Cloud Pub/Sub instead of Cloud Pub/Sub pushing messages to Cloud Dataflow.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>Answer:  B
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <question>You want to use Google Stackdriver Logging to monitor Google BigQuery usage. You need an instant notification to be sent to your monitoring tool when new data is appended to a certain table using an insert job, but you do not want to receive notifications for other tables. What should you do?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Make a call to the Stackdriver API to list all logs, and apply an advanced filter.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>In the Stackdriver logging admin interface, and enable a log sink export to BigQuery.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>In the Stackdriver logging admin interface, enable a log sink export to Google Cloud Pub/Sub, and subscribe to the topic from your monitoring tool.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Using the Stackdriver API, create a project sink with advanced log filter to export to Pub/Sub, and subscribe to the topic from your monitoring tool.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>Answer:  B
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Your company is in a highly regulated industry. One of your requirements is to ensure individual users have access only to the minimum amount of information required to do their jobs. You want to enforce this requirement with Google BigQuery. Which three approaches can you take? (Choose three.)</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Disable writes to certain tables.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Restrict access to tables by role.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Ensure that the data is encrypted at all times.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Restrict BigQuery API access to approved users.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Segregate data across multiple tables or databases.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use Google Stackdriver Audit Logging to determine policy violations.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>Answer:  BDF
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Your company’s customer and order databases are often under heavy load. This makes performing analytics against them difficult without harming operations. The databases are in a MySQL cluster, with nightly backups taken using mysqldump. You want to perform analytics with minimal impact on operations. What should you do?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Add a node to the MySQL cluster and build an OLAP cube there.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use an ETL tool to load the data from MySQL into Google BigQuery.
</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Connect an on-premises Apache Hadoop cluster to MySQL and perform ETL.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Mount the backups to Google Cloud SQL, and then process the data using Google Cloud Dataproc.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>Answer:  C
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Your company has hired a new data scientist who wants to perform complicated analyses across very large datasets stored in Google Cloud Storage and in a Cassandra cluster on Google Compute Engine. The scientist primarily wants to create labelled data sets for machine learning projects, along with some visualization tasks. She reports that her laptop is not powerful enough to perform her tasks and it is slowing her down. You want to help her perform her tasks. What should you do?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Run a local version of Jupiter on the laptop.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Grant the user access to Google Cloud Shell.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Host a visualization tool on a VM on Google Compute Engine.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Deploy Google Cloud Datalab to a virtual machine (VM) on Google Compute Engine.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>Answer:  B
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You are building a model to make clothing recommendations. You know a user’s fashion preference is likely to change over time, so you build a data pipeline to stream new data back to the model as it becomes available.
How should you use this data to train the model?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Continuously retrain the model on just the new data.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Continuously retrain the model on a combination of existing data and the new data.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Train on the existing data while using the new data as your test set.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Train on the new data while using the existing data as your test set.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>Answer:  D
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <question>You are building a model to predict whether or not it will rain on a given day. You have thousands of input features and want to see if you can improve training speed by removing some features while having a minimum effect on model accuracy. What can you do?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Eliminate features that are highly correlated to the output labels.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Combine highly co-dependent features into one representative feature.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Instead of feeding in each feature individually, average their values in batches of 3.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Remove the features that have null values for more than 50% of the training records.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>Answer:  B
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Flowlogistic’s CEO wants to gain rapid insight into their customer base so his sales team can be better informed in the field. This team is not very technical, so they’ve purchased a visualization tool to simplify the creation of BigQuery reports. However, they’ve been overwhelmed by all the data in the table, and are spending a lot of money on queries trying to find the data they need. You want to solve their problem in the most cost-effective way. What should you do?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Export the data into a Google Sheet for virtualization.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Create an additional table with only the necessary columns.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Create a view on the table to present to the virtualization tool.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Create identity and access management (IAM) roles on the appropriate columns, so only they appear in a query.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>Answer:  C
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <question>You need to compose visualization for operations teams with the following requirements:
Telemetry must include data from all 50,000 installations for the most recent 6 weeks (sampling once every minute)
The report must not be more than 3 hours delayed from live data.
The actionable report should only show suboptimal links.
Most suboptimal links should be sorted to the top.
Suboptimal links can be grouped and filtered by regional geography.
User response time to load the report must be <5 seconds.
You create a data source to store the last 6 weeks of data, and create visualizations that allow viewers to see multiple date ranges, distinct geographic regions, and unique installation types. You always show the latest data without any changes to your visualizations. You want to avoid creating and updating new visualizations each month. What should you do?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Look through the current data and compose a series of charts and tables, one for each possible combination of criteria.
 algorithm should you use?</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Look through the current data and compose a small set of generalized charts and tables bound to criteria filters that allow value selection.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Export the data to a spreadsheet, compose a series of charts and tables, one for each possible combination of criteria, and spread them across multiple tabs.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Load the data into relational database tables, write a Google App Engine application that queries all rows, summarizes the data across each criteria, and then renders results using the Google Charts and visualization API.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>Answer:  B
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Your company has recently grown rapidly and now ingesting data at a significantly higher rate than it was previously. You manage the daily batch MapReduce analytics jobs in Apache Hadoop. However, the recent increase in data has meant the batch jobs are falling behind. You were asked to recommend ways the development team could increase the responsiveness of the analytics without increasing costs. What should you recommend they do?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Rewrite the job in Pig.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Rewrite the job in Apache Spark.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Increase the size of the Hadoop cluster.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Decrease the size of the Hadoop cluster but also rewrite the job in Hive.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>Answer:  A
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You work for a manufacturing plant that batches application log files together into a single log file once a day at 2:00 AM. You have written a Google Cloud Dataflow job to process that log file. You need to make sure the log file in processed once per day as inexpensively as possible. What should you do?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Change the processing job to use Google Cloud Dataproc instead.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Manually start the Cloud Dataflow job each morning when you get into the office.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Create a cron job with Google App Engine Cron Service to run the Cloud Dataflow job.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Configure the Cloud Dataflow job as a streaming job so that it processes the log data immediately.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>Answer:  C
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You are deploying a new storage system for your mobile application, which is a media streaming service. You decide the best fit is Google Cloud Datastore. You have entities with multiple properties, some of which can take on multiple values. For example, in the entity ‘Movie’ the property ‘actors’ and the property ‘tags’ have multiple values but the property ‘date released’ does not. A typical query would ask for all movies with actor=<actorname> ordered by date_released or all movies with tag=Comedy ordered by date_released. How should you avoid a combinatorial explosion in the number of indexes?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Option A</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Option
B.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Option C</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Option D

   </entry>
  <entry>
    <question> </detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>Answer:  A

Which TensorFlow function can you use to configure a categorical column if you don't know all of the possible values for that column?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>categorical_column_with_vocabulary_list</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>categorical_column_with_hash_bucket</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>categorical_column_with_unknown_values</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>sparse_column_with_keys</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>Answer:  B
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>What is the HBase Shell for Cloud Bigtable?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>The HBase shell is a GUI based interface that performs administrative tasks, such as creating and deleting tables.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>The HBase shell is a command-line tool that performs administrative tasks, such as creating and deleting tables.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>The HBase shell is a hypervisor based shell that performs administrative tasks, such as creating and deleting new</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>The HBase shell is a command-line tool that performs only user account management functions to grant access to</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>Answer:  B
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Dataproc clusters contain many configuration files. To update these files, you will need to use the --properties option. file_prefix:property= .</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>details</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>value</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>null</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>id</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>Answer:  B
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Which of these rules apply when you add preemptible workers to a Dataproc cluster (select 2 answers)?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Preemptible workers cannot use persistent disk.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Preemptible workers cannot store data.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>If a preemptible worker is reclaimed, then a replacement worker must be added manually.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>A Dataproc cluster cannot have only preemptible workers.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>Answer:  BD
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>How can you get a neural network to learn about relationships between categories in a categorical feature?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Create a multi-hot column</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Create a one-hot column</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Create a hash bucket</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Create an embedding column</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>Answer:  D
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Which of the following is not true about Dataflow pipelines?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Pipelines are a set of operations</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Pipelines represent a data processing job</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Pipelines represent a directed graph of steps</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Pipelines can share data between instances</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>Answer:  D
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <question>What are the minimum permissions needed for a service account used with Google Dataproc?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Execute to Google Cloud Storage; write to Google Cloud Logging</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Write to Google Cloud Storage; read to Google Cloud Logging</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Execute to Google Cloud Storage; execute to Google Cloud Logging</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Read and write to Google Cloud Storage; write to Google Cloud Logging</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>Answer:  D
  </entry>


  <entry>
    <question>Which of the following is NOT true about Dataflow pipelines?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Dataflow pipelines are tied to Dataflow, and cannot be run on any other runner</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Dataflow pipelines can consume data from other Google Cloud services</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Dataflow pipelines can be programmed in Java</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Dataflow pipelines use a unified programming model, so can work both with streaming and batch data sources</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>Answer:  A
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>Which software libraries are supported by Cloud Machine Learning Engine?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Theano and TensorFlow</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Theano and Torch</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>TensorFlow</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>TensorFlow and Torch</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>Answer:  C
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <question>You work for a mid-sized enterprise that needs to move its operational system transaction data from an on-premises database to GCP. The database is about 20 TB in size. Which database should you choose?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Cloud SQL</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Cloud Bigtable</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Cloud Spanner</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Cloud Datastore</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>Answer:  A
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <question>Your company needs to upload their historic data to Cloud Storage. The security rules don’t allow access from external IPs to their on-premises resources. After an initial upload, they will add new data from existing
on-premises applications every day. What should they do?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Execute gsutil rsync from the on-premises servers.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use Cloud Dataflow and write the data to Cloud Storage.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Write a job template in Cloud Dataproc to perform the data transfer.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Install an FTP server on a Compute Engine VM to receive the files and move them to Cloud Storage.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>Answer:  B
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>You are designing a data processing pipeline. The pipeline must be able to scale automatically as load increases. Messages must be processed at least once, and must be ordered within windows of 1 hour. How should you design the solution?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use Apache Kafka for message ingestion and use Cloud Dataproc for streaming analysis.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use Apache Kafka for message ingestion and use Cloud Dataflow for streaming analysis.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use Cloud Pub/Sub for message ingestion and Cloud Dataproc for streaming analysis.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use Cloud Pub/Sub for message ingestion and Cloud Dataflow for streaming analysis.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>Answer:  C
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <question>5

You are operating a streaming Cloud Dataflow pipeline. Your engineers have a new version of the pipeline with a different windowing algorithm and triggering strategy. You want to update the running pipeline with the new version. You want to ensure that no data is lost during the update. What should you do?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Update the Cloud Dataflow pipeline inflight by passing the --update option with the --jobName set to the existing job name</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Update the Cloud Dataflow pipeline inflight by passing the --update option with the --jobName set to a new unique job name</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Stop the Cloud Dataflow pipeline with the Cancel optio</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Create a new Cloud Dataflow job with the updated code</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Stop the Cloud Dataflow pipeline with the Drain optio</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Create a new Cloud Dataflow job with the updated code</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>Answer:  A
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>6

You are responsible for writing your company’s ETL pipelines to run on an Apache Hadoop cluster. The pipeline will require some checkpointing and splitting pipelines. Which method should you use to write the pipelines?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>PigLatin using Pig</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>HiveQL using Hive</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Java using MapReduce</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Python using MapReduce</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>Answer:  D
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>2

You need to create a data pipeline that copies time-series transaction data so that it can be queried from within BigQuery by your data science team for analysis. Every hour, thousands of transactions are updated with a new status. The size of the intitial dataset is 1.5 PB, and it will grow by 3 TB per day. The data is heavily structured, and your data science team will build machine learning models based on this data. You want to maximize performance and usability for your data science team. Which two strategies should you adopt? Choose 2 answers.</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Denormalize the data as must as possible.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Preserve the structure of the data as much as possible.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use BigQuery UPDATE to further reduce the size of the dataset.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Develop a data pipeline where status updates are appended to BigQuery instead of updated. E. Copy a daily snapshot of transaction data to Cloud Storage and store it as an Avro fil</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use BigQuery’ssupport for external data sources to query.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>Answer:  DE
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>4

You are operating a Cloud Dataflow streaming pipeline. The pipeline aggregates events from a Cloud Pub/Sub subscription source, within a window, and sinks the resulting aggregation to a Cloud Storage bucket. The source has consistent throughput. You want to monitor an alert on behavior of the pipeline with Cloud Stackdriver to ensure that it is processing data. Which Stackdriver alerts should you create?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>An alert based on a decrease of subscription/num_undelivered_messages for the source and a rate of change increase of instance/storage/used_bytes for the


destination</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>An alert based on an increase of subscription/num_undelivered_messages for the source and a rate of change decrease of instance/storage/used_bytes for the destination</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>An alert based on a decrease of instance/storage/used_bytes for the source and a rate of change increase of subscription/num_undelivered_messages for the destination</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>An alert based on an increase of instance/storage/used_bytes for the source and a rate of change decrease of subscription/num_undelivered_messages for the destination</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>Answer:  B
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <question>5

You architect a system to analyze seismic data. Your extract, transform, and load (ETL) process runs as a series of MapReduce jobs on an Apache Hadoop cluster. The ETL process takes days to process a data set because some steps are computationally expensive. Then you discover that a sensor calibration step has been omitted. How should you change your ETL process to carry out sensor calibration systematically in the future?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Modify the transformMapReduce jobs to apply sensor calibration before they do anything else.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Introduce a new MapReduce job to apply sensor calibration to raw data, and ensure all other MapReduce jobs are chained after this.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Add sensor calibration data to the output of the ETL process, and document that all users need to apply sensor calibration themselves.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Develop an algorithm through simulation to predict variance of data output from the last MapReduce job based on calibration factors, and apply the correction to all data.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>Answer:  A
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>8

You’re using Bigtable for a real-time application, and you have a heavy load that is a mix of read and writes. You’ve recently identified an additional use case and need to perform hourly an analytical job to calculate certain statistics across the whole database. You need to ensure both the reliability of your production application as well as the analytical workload.
What should you do?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Export Bigtable dump to GCS and run your analytical job on top of the exported files.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Add a second cluster to an existing instance with a multi-cluster routing, use live-traffic app profile for your regular workload and batch-analytics profile for the analytics workload.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Add a second cluster to an existing instance with a single-cluster routing, use live-traffic app profile for your regular workload and batch-analytics profile for the analytics workload.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Increase the size of your existing cluster twice and execute your analytics workload on your new resized cluster.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>Answer:  B
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <question>4

You want to archive data in Cloud Storage. Because some data is very sensitive, you want to use the “Trust No One” (TNO) approach to encrypt your data to prevent the cloud provider staff from decrypting your data. What should you do?</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use gcloud kms keys create to create a symmetric ke</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Then use gcloud kms encrypt to encrypt each archival file with the key and unique additional authenticated data (AAD). Use gsutil cp to upload each encrypted file to the Cloud Storage bucket, and keep the AAD outside of Google Cloud.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use gcloud kms keys create to create a symmetric ke</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Then use gcloud kms encrypt to encrypt each archival file with the ke</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use gsutil cp to upload each encrypted file to the Cloud Storage bucke</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Manually destroy the key previously used for encryption, and rotate the key once and rotate the key once.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Specify customer-supplied encryption key (CSEK) in the .boto configuration fil</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use gsutil cp to upload each archival file to the Cloud Storage bucke</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Save the CSEK in Cloud Memorystore as permanent storage of the secret.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Specify customer-supplied encryption key (CSEK) in the .boto configuration fil</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Use gsutil cp to upload each archival file to the Cloud Storage bucke
L. Save the CSEK in a different project that only the security team can access.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>Answer:  B

</bank>