<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<bank>
  <topic>PDE12 - Brain Dump (google.exambible.professional-data-engineer.pdf.exam.2023-oct-16.by.baron.100q.vce)</topic>
  <!-- STRUCTURE DEFINITION:
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <question>XXX</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>XXX</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>
  </entry>
  -->

  <entry>
    <question>Your company produces 20,000 files every hour. Each data file is formatted as a comma separated values (CSV) file that is less than 4 KB. All files must be ingested on Google Cloud Platform before they can be processed. Your company site has a 200 ms latency to Google Cloud, and your Internet connection bandwidth is limited as 50 Mbps. You currently deploy a secure FTP (SFTP) server on a virtual machine in Google Compute Engine as the data ingestion point. A local SFTP client runs on a dedicated machine to transmit the CSV files as is. The goal is to make reports with data from the previous day available to the executives by 10:00 a.m. each day. This design is barely able to keep up with the current volume, even though the bandwidth utilization is rather low.
You are told that due to seasonality, your company expects the number of files to double for the next three months. Which two actions should you take? (choose two.)</question>
    <answer>
      <options>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Introduce data compression for each file to increase the rate file of file transfer.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Contact your internet service provider (ISP) to increase your maximum bandwidth to at least 100 Mbps.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Redesign the data ingestion process to use gsutil tool to send the CSV files to a storage bucket in parallel.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Assemble 1,000 files into a tape archive (TAR) fil</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Transmit the TAR files instead, and disassemble the CSV files in the cloud upon receiving them.</detail>
        </option>
        <option>
          <valid>false</valid>
          <detail>Create an S3-compatible storage endpoint in your network, and use Google Cloud Storage Transfer Service to transfer on-premices data to the designated storage bucket.</detail>
        </option>
      </options>
    </answer>Answer:  CE

  </entry>


</bank>